Abdul Malik Arshath

M malikarshath@gmail.com

ttps://malikarshath.github.io/

1 +91-9942441846

https://www.linkedin.com/in/abdul-malik-arshath-897661132 https://trailblazer.me/id/malikarshath

Salesforce Developer Developing what is necessary...!

A software engineer with 3+ years of experience who constantly loves to develop efficient solution and learn across several disciplines. And confident in providing efficient output as a valuable resource. Learned what is necessary. If work demands happy to learn new skill.

Education

B.S. ABDUR RAHMAN CRESCENT INSTITUTE OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY, CHENNAI, INDIA Bachelor of Technology in Mechanical Engineering

July 2013-*May* 2017

NAGAMANI AMMAL MEMORIAL MATRICULATION HR. SEC SCHOOL, CUMBUM, TAMIL NADU, INDIA

March 2013

12th Grade, Tamil Nadu State Board

NAGAMANI AMMAL MEMORIAL MATRICULATION HR. SEC SCHOOL, CUMBUM, TAMIL NADU, INDIA

March 2011

10th Grade, Tamil Nadu Matriculation Board

Technical Skills

Check out my skills at github

Programming HTML,CSS,Apex,Python,JavaScript,SOQL,SOSL,SQLite

Version Control

IDF Visual Studio, pycharm

Experience

STRATOS STUDIO Salesforce Consultant

May 2022- Present

- Resource Allocation Project based on the Salesforce Sales Cloud platform related to creation of Leads and Opportunities. Working on the CRM Digital Marketing App managing Salesforce Data Model -Standard & Custom sObjects, fields, relationships, custom settings, custom labels & custom Metadata
- Worked on the Automation of various Business requirements through **Process Builders**, workflows, Time-triggered and Screen flows in order to accomplish various update Operations on the incoming leads, sending Alerts, Inactivation and Lead Ingestion of guest user in Salesforce.

- Created various Formulas, Validation rules to satisfy complex business requirements.
- Worked on Data Security Model creation of Profiles, roles, users, permission sets & sharing settings,
 editing Field-level security, OWD & System Permissions.
- Salesforce UI customization via Page layouts, search & compact layouts, record types, list views, buttons & actions.
- Used Data Management tools data import wizard & data loader.
- Financial services project based on Sales cloud- worked on onboarding of new Customers.
- Worked on **Triggers** for updates and Deletion on functionalities that needed out of box solutions.
- Written Numerous **Test classes** for code coverage in-line with Governor limits,
- Worked on Asynchronous Apex- Batchable Apex, Schedulable Apex for updating mass records on various objects.

CAPGEMINI ENGINEERING

Associate Consultant 1 Year: June 2021 - May 2022

- Created page layouts, search layouts, custom links, and related lists.
- Configured pick lists, dependent pick lists, lookups, junction objects, master-detail relationships, validation rules, and formula fields.
- Created Salesforce Objects and related metadata necessary to support customization across instances.
- Initiated Basic org setup and creating custom objects and facilitated reviews throughout the project.
- Performed requirements analysis, and imported a huge data using the Data import wizard,
- Data Loader and Workbench based on business requirements.

DESIGNTECH SYSTEM LTD (SEG AUTOMOTIVE INDIA PRIVATE LTD, BANGALORE, INDIA)

Junior Engineer Technical Service

- Coordinating the Global ECR team for modifying the Starter Motor/ Generator and its sub assembly,
- Responsible for preparing and presenting mechanical design at design reviews along with support design teams.
- Responsible for reporting progress of all assigned task to the Global Coordinator and project Management teams.
- Distributing task to all the designers and presenting the status of ECR in the CMI meeting.
- Manage changes through formalized process (ECR).

Certification

- ✓ Salesforce Certified Administrator
- ✓ Salesforce Certified Platform App Builder
- √ Salesforce Certified Platform Developer I
- ✓ **Python For Everybody** specialization in Coursera
- ✓ C# Basics for Beginners: Learn C# Fundamentals by Coding in Udemy
- ✓ **C# Intermediate: Classes, Interfaces and OOP** in Udemy





2 Years: February 2019-February 2021

